# **BIJAY KADARIYA**

kadbijay@gmail.com | 804-937-6758 | Fairfax VA

# Summary

Experienced Front-End Developer specializing in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Team player with a military background and leadership qualities. Collaborates effectively with government clients and cross-functional teams to identify needs, optimize design usability, and enhance performance. Trusted by the Department of Defense with an active Secret Clearance for handling sensitive information.

#### **Skills**

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Libraries and Frameworks: Express.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, React
- Databases and other: MongoDB, Git, GitHub, Photoshop, Debugger tool, SharePoint Online, SharePoint Designer 2013, Visual Studio Code, notepad++
- Interpersonal skills: Strong writing and verbal communication skills to relay technical information to non-technical audiences.

# **Experience**

08/2022 - Current Synergetic

Information System

Inc

Fort Meade, MD

#### **Application Developer**

- Built a data visualization chart (Sunburst Chart) using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and D3 library to visualize the project status
- Experienced Using SharePoint Online and SharePoint Designer 2013
- Improvised an existing web page by adding features such as buttons, a scroll bar, a navigation bar, and hyperlinks to make the web page efficient and user-friendly for clients.

08/2020 - 08/2022 Brightemerges (intern)

Fairfax, VA

# **Front-End Developer**

- Designed and built prototype web pages utilizing HTML and CSS for a user-friendly and visually appealing interface
- Experienced using HTML Tags, and attributes to create websites with components such as Header, Footer, Navigation, logins, forms, etc.

04/2019 - 04/2022

U.S Army Winchester, VA

#### **Logistic and Supply Specialist**

- Managed and coordinated the movement of personnel, equipment, and supplies to ensure operational readiness and support mission success
- Updated charts and reports to track inventories resulting in 100% accountability
- Tracked, controlled, audited, and updated inventories, deadline reports, and faults using the ERP system.

# **Projects**

### **Project: National Holiday**

- Created By: Bijay Kadariya
- Link: https://github.com/bijaykadariya123/ProjectUnit1

- List of Technologies HTML,CSS,JavaScript,JQuery,AJAX
- Built a responsive web application utilizing HTML CSS JS, JQuery and Ajax API requests to determine the National Holiday of United States

## **Project: CountryPedia**

- Created By: Bijay Kadariya
- Link: https://github.com/bijaykadariya123/Project2
- List of Technologies HTML,CSS,JavaScript,Express,MongoDB, EJS, Bootstrap
- This project will populate the Countries Name and flag on landing page and will be able to create Read update and delete countries and its information

# **Education and Training**

Expected in 10/2023 **General Assembly Remote** 

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.